ADAM HUSAIN

Contact Number: **805 618 5251** | Contact Email: medaman@gmail.com
GitHub: https://github.com/medaman | Portfolio: http://www.adamscode.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/adamhusain

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Full Stack Web Developer and former IT Business Development Manager with experience in Javascript, JQuery, HTML5, CSS3, Node.js, Express, MySQL, Sequelize, AJAX, Bootstrap 3/4, MongoDB, Data Visualization. Has managed many IT projects with a high level focus on requirements gathering, planning and client satisfaction.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- ✓ Javascript, JQuery, HTML5, CSS3, Node.js, Express, MySQL, Sequelize, AJAX, Bootstrap 3/4, MongoDB, Data Visualization
- ✓ Adobe Photoshop, Microsoft Office Suite

EDUCATION

University of California, Irvine, CA, USA

June 2017 to Present

Full Stack Web Development

An intensive 24-week long program dedicated to designing and building web applications. Skills learned consisted of HTML, CSS, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase, Node.js, MySQL and more.

Symbiosis Centre for Information Technology, India

August 2010 to April 2012

Masters of Business Administration (MBA) in IT Business Management

Symbiosis Arts and Commerce College, India

August 2007 to April 2010

Bachelors of Commerce

PROJECTS

<u>Dancing Salmon</u> - Discography and Music Video Search Tool

- An advanced tool to search for information on Music Artists and their discography.
- Uses 4 different APIs to fetch information
- Additional functionality includes:
 - o Upcoming concert information with ability to Book Tickets
 - Watching Music Videos
 - Internet Radio Player
- Uses HTML, CSS, Bootstrap 4, Javascript, JQuery, AJAX, and Google Firebase
- Team of 4 Developers
- Award winning project.

- http://www.adamscode.com/dancing-salmon
- https://github.com/medaman/dancing-salmon

<u>Hangman</u> - Word guessing game

- Hangman game built using Javascript and Bootstrap with an intuitive and mobile-friendly UI.
- Uses HTML, CSS, Bootstrap 3, and Javascript
- Sole Developer
- http://www.adamscode.com/hangman
- https://github.com/medaman/hangman

Star Wars RPG ame

- An RPG game with Star Wars Theme with an intuitive and clean UI.
- Uses HTML, CSS, Bootstrap 3, Javascript and JQuery.
- Sole Developer
- http://www.adamscode.com/star-wars-rpg
- https://github.com/medaman/star-wars-rpg

Flashcard Maker - A tool to create and use flashcards

- Two types of flashcards can be made. Regular and Cloze.
- Uses Node.js, Javascript, NPM, Inquirer, and FS
- Sole Developer
- https://github.com/medaman/flashcard-maker

WORK EXPERIENCE

Sigma Infosolutions - Business Development Manager - June 2013 to August 2017 **Aryaka Networks** - Demand Generation Executive - April 2012 to June 2013

PERSONAL DOSSIER

HOBBIES AND INTERESTS

- ✓ Avid Gamer
- ✓ Cricket Player

Adam Husain